# Dimitris Mavrokapnidis

#### Address:

22 Calvert Avenue, E27JP, London, UK **E-mail:** 

dimitris.mavrokapnidis@gmail.com Mobile:

(+44) 7586545238

#### **Profile**

5+ years of research and working experience in complex systems thinking, information modeling, data science, and the Internet of Things in the context of the built environment.

**Driven by** the creation of practical **software** and **data architectures** that provide scalable solutions to complex problems and novel ideas.

## **Technical Skills**

RDF, SHACL, SPARQL 00000 00000 Python UML 00000 Neo4j, GraphDB 00000 ••000 JavaScript ETL 00000 XML, JSON 00000 IFC, gbXML Revit, Dynamo EnergyPlus 00000 Modelica

#### Languages

English
Greek
French

•••••
•••••

#### **Awards**



1st prize in Hackathon of LDAC 2022 Summer School at Cercedilla Spain https://linkedbuildingdata.ne t/ldac2022/summerschool/

### **Interests**

- Football
- Snowboarding
- Travelling

# **Professional Experience**



Sep. 2020 - present London, UK

#### **Research Fellow**

University College London

#### Research Fellow in Semantic Technologies for Digital Twins

- Designed and led the implementation of a scalable Data Lake and Building Analytics Platform architecture for EU's Horizon 2020 project "DigiBuild"
  - o Providing technical guidance to the development of UCL's Marshgate Digital Twin pilot.
- Researching the intersection of Knowledge Graphs and LLMs for querying building data, using Langchain, ChromaDB, and OpenAl's API.

#### Marie-Curie Research Fellow in Cloud-BIM

- Extensive training in OpenBIM, Cloud and Semantic Technologies.
- Developed ETL tools, data quality checking mechanism and a logical inferencing engine to automate building data integrations using ifcopenshell, RDFlib and pySHACL python libraries.
- Created SeeQ: a Python library to facilitate development of portable applications
  - o Presented work and collaborated with Siemens' AG R&D department at Zug, Switzerland.
- Presented research outputs in 5 different conferences.



**Sep. 2022 - Jan. 2023**Golden, Colorado, USA

# **Computer Science Intern**

Colorado School of Mines

- Collaborated with Dr. Gabe Fierro to devise a novel programming abstraction for portable smart building applications.
- Create and test a set of portable smart building applications based on Brick Schema.



**Jan. 2020 - Jul. 2021** Atlanta, Georgia, USA

#### Research Assistant

Network Dynamics Lab (NDL), Georgia Tech

• Implemented time-series forecasting models and computer vision algorithms for the development of a Smart City Digital Twin prototype for the City of Columbus, Georgia.



Nov. 2017 - Aug. 2018
Athens, Greece

# **Software Developer**

**ACE-Hellas** 

• Collaborated with software engineers and supported the development of the Optimisation Computing Platform (OCP) to include Energy and CO2 emissions parameters.

# **Education**



# PhD, Enabling Smart Building Operation at Scale University College London (UCL)

2020 - present London, UK

Minor: Knowledge Representation and Graph Databases

• Research Topic: Investigating scalable information modelling practices to facilitate data discovery and application development for large building portfolios.



London, UK

MSc, Smart Buildings and Digital Engineering University College London (UCL),

- 1-year program ("Distinction") with focus on Building Physics, Building Automation, Energy Management Systems, HVAC Control, Machine Learning
- Thesis: "Model Predictive Control for Buildings-to-Grid integration using dynamic electricity pricing"



**2012 - 2017**Athens, Greece

# MEng, Civil and Environmental Engineering

National Technical University of Athens (NTUA)

- **5-year program**: Applied Maths and Physics with focus on Computational Structural Optimisation and Sustainability
- **Thesis** (Excellent Grade 10/10): "Environmental assessment of cost-optimised structural systems in tall buildings" Published in Journal of Building Engineering